

% 7827598996☑ link2pk@gmail.com⑨ Gurgaon/Anywhere

Creative HTML developer with 6+ years of experience having an eye for typography, visual aspects, and responsiveness of UI layouts.

Highly proficient in HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Git, Photoshop, Sketch, Figma, Zeplin, and others to build beautiful and interactive user interfaces for web and hybrid applications that drive business growth.

SKILLS

- Expert in mobile-first responsive UI development.
- PSD/Sketch/Figma/Zeplin to HTML conversion.
- To collaborate with designers for design(UI/UX) feasibility on Frontend and to provide efficient solutions
- To Provide support to backend developers for UI integration and implementation.
- Cross-browser/device compatibility check.
- jQuery/JS plugins implementation.
- Git for keeping source code.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Appster LLP

Software Engineer, Appster LLP

Apr 2016 - Oct 2017

Web Developer, Appster LLP

Dec 2014 - Mar 2016

- Revamped the entire frontend of apppster.com.au/appsterhq.com from scratch along with one of my colleagues and implemented animations and plugins using CSS3, jQuery, and JavaScript. Also, Worked as a product owner for 3 weeks.
- Worked on all kinds of web applications for clients as per their satisfaction.
- Was part of QIII-Platinum Club 2016 for best project.
- Collaborated with graphic designers and backend developers for best UX.
- Followed agile development and daily scrum meetings.
- Reviewed client feedbacks on basecamp and JIRA.

Designer, Convergent Technologies

Mar 2014 - Dec 2014

- Was hired for their client, which was Samsung.
- Worked for top clients like Apple, Eicher, NIIT, and other small and medium-sized businesses.
- Created designs for their CMS and converted that into HTML.
- Provided support to backend developers for UI integration.
- Created banners and background images for special events and holidays.

Web Designer, Sagacious Softwares(now Digital HIVE)

Aug 2013 - Mar 2014

- Designed websites using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Converted PSDs and designs into HTML for their clients.
- Used Bootstrap framework and ¡Query for plugins integration.
- Tutored junior web designer for UI implementation.

UI Designer, Webreinvent Technologies Pvt Ltd

Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

- Learned and started working on HTML and CSS.
- Learned Adobe Products for websites and logo design.
- Started using jQuery sliders and plugins in projects.
- Worked on different projects with a short deadline.

EDUCATION

MSc in Information Technology, De Montfort University, Leicester

2011

BE in Electronics and Communications, Institute of Technology & Management, Gurgaon (now NorthCap University)

2008

SOME PROJECTS

https://prod.savvyapp.com.au/adviser

https://savvyapp.com.au

https://app.six8.com.au

http://www.consultthompson.com

https://www.rmrmarmo.com

https://www.360degreeworld.com

https://tresure.com.au

https://goplanetnow.com

http://bontatank.com.au

https://www.appster.com.au

https://www.finalcall.com.au

http://www.streamhear.com

http://www.enfactum.com